## **CASEY VERICA**

💌 cwverica@gmail.com 🔾 caseyverica.info 📞 6093281530 🕈 Portland, OR in cwverica 🗘 cwverica

#### **SUMMARY**

As a life-long STEM enthusiast, I've dabbled in and out of technology since I was 12 years old. I'm a fast learner who's recently completed training in multiple programming languages, frameworks, and tools, while working 1-on-1 with industry professionals and completing two full applications in a 9 month boot camp. I enjoy working on a team, and am looking for a back-end role in a challenging but supportive environment.

#### SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: Python, JavaScipt, SQL, HTML/CSS, Java FRONT-END FRAMEWORKS: WTForms, Bootstrap, JQuery, XML/JSON, React, Ajax, Tkinter, Turtle (python) BACK-END FRAMEWORKS: Flask, PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy, NodeJS, WTForms, Express, SQLite, Django SPOKEN LANGUAGES: English, French, Spanish

## **PROJECTS**

#### Quixr

- Created Quixr: An app to chose a cocktail recipe
- Used Python, Flask, and SQLAlchemy to create a RESTful back-end
- Used PostgreSQL as a database to store user and drink information, and bcrypt to encrypt user passwords
- Used HTML/CSS and Bootstrap to create an intuitive front-end with a responsive design

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Springboard Software Engineering Career Track Fellow

- 700+ hours of hands-on course material, with 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight
- Mastered skills in front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms.
- Completion of 4 in-depth portfolio projects (2 from ideation to completion, 2 from skeleton code to completion).

## Squaw Valley Ski Resort

Lead Bartender · Nov. 2015 to Mar. 2020, Nov. 2015 to Mar. 2020 · Olympic Valley, CA

- Engaged with, built relationships with, and anticipated the needs of 200+ Guests at daily operations venue.
- Communicated with management and sales team to plan, lead, and execute \$50k+ events with event staff at events venues.
- Thrived in fast-paced, high-pressure environment while maintaining a positive, can-do attitude.

#### **EDUCATION**

Springboard Software Engineering Career Track, Certification · Feb. 2021 to Current 9-month intensive course in Software Engineering methodologies and technologies

Rutgers University, School of Engineering · Aug. 2004 to Apr. 2006 Studies focused on Physics, Chemistry, and Higher Math